KARIM LAMEER

07921 977 067 | klameer@yahoo.com

INTRODUCTORY PROFILE -

Commercially aware and qualified business data analyst delivering technical solutions at every stage of the data science pipeline. Helps facilitate evidence-based decision making and planning with data analytical thinking. Diverse experience both as a freelance consultant and a contractor in organisations including FTSE 100 companies both in the UK and abroad.

CORE COMPETENCIES -

Financial, Data, Statistical Modelling | Data Consolidation | Building Data Pipelines | Complex Requirements Gathering | Reporting and Report Streamlining | App Development | Client Relations Global Teams | Financial / Operational Data Consolidation | Procedural Streamlining | Agile Working | Business / Investment Appraisal

Data Analysis MS Excel/MS Access, Python (Pandas, Numpy and Scipy, Matplotlib)

Application Development Python Frameworks Flask and Django

Enterprise Systems SAP in Finance GL, AR. AP, HR, Assets, Hyperion, Essbase, Sun Financials,

COGNOS and SalesForce

Database / Reporting SQL Server, SSIS, SSAS, SSRS, Oracle, MySQL, SQLAlchemy

Programming Python, VBA, SQL, R, HTML and JavaScript

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE -

Jemka Consulting

Financial Data Modeller and Reporting Analyst

09.2017-04.2018

Statistical data analysis of share price movements and profiling on companies for evidence-based investment portfolio decisions. Created on Python Pandas library (including MS Excel) with presentation on the Flask web framework:

- Extracted and consolidated large datasets and optimised for reporting.
- Carried out statistical analysis on the data and profiled companies and price movement. Created overall summaries for easy reporting.
- Applied analysis to new data via an API on the Python Flask web framework.
- Developed back testing model for various scenarios.

DELL / EMC (HSBC)

Financial Data Modeller

06.2017-09.2017

Teamed up with Global Account Specialists in creating proposal for HSBC data optimisation and rationalisation, working closely with storage experts and executives to ensure compliance with functional needs / requirements:

- Orchestrated consolidation of financial and operational data from various sources to build robust financial models for scenario analysis.
- Formulated high-level engagement strategy to optimise presentation of deliverables and benefits to clients
- Normalised datasets to create single best practice golden source of data for consistency over global team.
- Automated analysis and testing of systems using various programming environments including Python and VBA.

KARIM LAMEER

Page Two | 07921 977 067 | klameer@yahoo.com

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE continued —

DELL / EMC (Barclays / HSBC / Deutsche Bank)

Finance Business Analyst

05.2015-03.2016

Supported enterprise technology transformation projects through provision of finance business analysis focused on building complex financial / data models and optimising resources through processes streamlining. Connected with clients throughout implementation of evidence-based strategic decision-making:

- Created complex data and financial models for investment appraisal and benefits realisation tracking.
- Generated optimisation strategies based on automation and process improvements.
- Produced enhanced data models for customers in alignment with resource requirements.
- Developed and validated golden sources of data within programme to ensure standard and accurate reporting within sub projects.
- Delivered insight into strategic decision-making based on actual data evidence.
- Provided business case appraisal, analysis, and reporting.
- Built storage tier model that analysed client's existing storage metrics and recommended optimum storage tier. The model also suggested financial implications of adopting new storage tier.

Vodafone

Reporting and Finance Manager

03.2014-05.2015

Conducted financial and business case analysis for Vodafone Spring Programme – a £20B organisation-wide reinvestment project to deliver complex reporting requirement (financial / non-financial information). Provided ad hoc analysis as mandated by senior management for strategic initiatives:

- Completed business case analysis and consolidation covering hundreds of cases in alignment with programme objectives.
- Achieved financial reporting cube for interactive analysis / reporting through new process implementation for organisation of large amounts of unstructured data for expedited management reporting (using Excel, Access, VBA, SQL Server and Python).
- Improved reporting quality and timeliness by organising diverse, unstructured data from various sources into data reporting cube in alignment with stakeholder needs.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE -

Baxi UK - SAP Data Migration Analyst	2017
Arriva Group – Business Analyst	2017
Pitney Bowes – Senior Financial Business Analyst	2011-2014
Skype – Finance Business Analyst (Contract)	2010
NHS - Information Analyst (Contract)	2008-2010
MF Global – Finance Analyst (Contract)	2008
Hutchinson 3G – Business Analyst (Contract)	2007-2008
Vodafone – Finance Analyst (Contract)	2005-2007
Centrica – Business Analyst (Contract)	2005
02 - Systems Accountant (Contract)	2004-2005
Sri Lankan Airlines – Finance Executive	2002-2004

EDUCATION AND TRAINING —

CIMA (UK) - Associate Member	2002
MSc in Information Technology	2004
Microsoft Certification - SQL Server Developer	2009
Introduction to Data Science Coursera	2013
Computational Investing, Part 1 by Georgia Institute of Technology	2017
Data Science, a 10-course specialization by John Hopkins University	2018